大家吼哇，这里是牛老师，字幕翻译给虫
Hello people, this is NUSensei
你们有没有看过奥运会的射箭比赛，选手射出去后弓都会往前倒（摆弓）
I often get this question: why do Olympic archers drop their bows?
首先明确一点，不只有奥运会的反曲弓比赛会摆弓
Firstly it's not just the Olympic target style recurve archers that drop their bows
裸弓射手射标靶也会摆弓
Barebow target archers also drop their bows and some
有的复合弓射手也会，那这是为什么呢？
compound archers will do the same. Why do they do that?
原因很简单，射手没握住弓
There's a very simple explanation: they don't actually grip their bow
那你们肯定又奇怪了，为啥射手不想握住自己的弓呢？
You might be wondering: why would you not want to hold the bow?
你不想控制你的箭射得准吗？这就说到点子了
Don't you want to control it? And that's actually the point
紧握弓，反而会让你难以控制弓箭走向，接下来我会详细解释
Gripping the bow causes a loss of control and I'll show you why
用简易的裸弓会好解释
This is more apparent in a light barebow
许多学射箭的萌新有个坏毛病叫“死亡之握”(Death Grip)，他们会死死抓着弓不放
Many beginners who do archery have a habit called the death grip. They'll grip the bow really really tight
就像要把弓掐死一样，这在萌新阵营里非常常见
like choking the life out of the bow tight and you see this a lot on the line.
也非常正常，同时你也会看到他持弓的手一个劲发抖
It's quite a normal thing. You see some pull back at full draw and the hands are like white knuckles showing.
看上去贼紧张，结果呢？射出的箭也非常不稳定。
It's really tense and what happens when someone does that is that the shot becomes very shaky.
手臂、手指肌肉都在用力，互相影响，你就会发抖，箭就会不稳定
The tendons in the fingers and the hand counteract each other and you have shake, you have torque. It's quite unstable
反过来，如果你不那么紧紧握弓，就像比赛里那样
The complete opposite of that is not holding a bow at all, so what you find is the Olympic style archers will do this
专业的射手拉弦后，持弓的手就不用握住弓，实际上手指是完全松开的
They'll pull the string back and they're not holding the grip at all. The fingers are in fact off the riser.
没有之前紧握的压力，弓会很自然的紧靠你的虎口
With no uneven pressure on the grip what should happen is that the bow should sit naturally in the hand.
这里就有个问题了，我要是就这样撒手，弓就会跟着飞出去了
There is a problem if I let go. The bow is going to come flying out of my hand
所以人们会使用弓绳(Sling)，有缠在手指上的，有在手腕上的
That is why people use slings. They can be finger slings or wrist
作用就是连接弓和手，别让弓也飞出去
slings and the point of the sling is to wrap around the riser so it catches the bow when it drops
弓就应该掉出去的。掉出去才说明你没有死死握住弓
The bow is meant to drop. That shows us that you're not applying any pressure on the bow
这点很重要，因为射手和弓有肢体接触的只有两个点，持弓的手和拉弦的手
This is important because for an archer, there are only 2 physical contact points: the bow grip and the drawing hand
多数失误也都是发生在其中某个点上
Most of the mistakes that happen are due to one of these factors
当射手开始自由练习的时候，可能会有点紧张
When people start shooting freestyle they might get a little nervous
所以你经常能看到有的明明戴了弓绳的射手，还在紧握弓，射的时候就像这样
So, you often see people, even with the finger sling on, still hold onto the grip and they'll shoot like this
手指还在握住弓
fingers still on the grip and they'll hold onto it like that
这倒也算正常，因为其实训练一个固定的持弓姿势是有难度的
That's a fairly normal thing and it's kind of hard to train out the habit of hanging on to the bow
因为每次握姿都可能不太一样
because there is no way you can shoot with the same consistency if you're still gripping the bow
如果你是这样射箭的，尤其想射标靶
If you're shooting like this, especially shooting target
那就要学习一个，如何摆弓，让弓自然下落
you really should be teaching yourself to let go and let it drop
只要你会正确使用弓绳，那弓就不会摔地上
As long as your sling is correctly applied the bow will not fall down
而如果弓在下落，那你就没做错
and if it does fall down then you're doing it right
虽然弓自己可能会不高兴
Unfortunately, the bow might not like you for it
所以，正确的拉弓放箭姿势是这样的
So, a proper shot process and release and follow-through should look something like this
摆弓的动作有几种
There are several different ways people let the bow drop
多数射手会向前摆
Most archers will let the bow drop in front of them so it swings out this way
还有的会向外摆，或者让弓撞一下大腿
Other archers will let the bow swing outwards or let the bow hit their leg
这取决于射手的喜好，或者训练方法
It largely depends on several factors such as your preference or the way you were trained
有的人喜欢胳膊往外摆，有的喜欢往内
Again, some people naturally expand and swing outwards others prefer to keep it in line and swing it inwards
甭管哪种，最重要的一点是摆弓都必须是无意识的
The important thing is that the follow-through and the bow drop should not be a conscious action
摆弓不是在装逼，射手不是为了拍视频发B站才摆弓的
It's not a flair. The archers are not intentionally doing this for the camera
射手摆弓是因为他们没有紧握弓，这是很自然的事情
They're doing it because when they don't grip the bow, that's what naturally happens
还要就是对于裸弓来说，弓可能不会往前摆，而是往后
Also note that if you're shooting barebow, the bow might actually tilt backwards rather swing forwards
多数裸弓重心会偏后，除非你前面放很多配重
Most barebows tend to be back heavy unless you put on a lot of front weight.
想要像电视上那样摆弓的话就得用整套配重加竞赛级反曲弓
The only way to get that majestic swing is if you're  using a full stabilizer setup with the Olympic recurves
另外，摆弓这件事并不会影响射箭本身
Also note that the follow-through doesn't affect the shot itself
就算你射箭后来个阿姆斯特朗1080度回旋加速摆弓都改变不了结果
It doesn't matter if you twirl it twice, do a 360 spin and brush your hair back
开弓都没有回头箭，你之前瞄哪就是哪
The arrow has already left the bow so it's going to hit where you pointed the bow at
跟你之后咋样没关系
not what you do after the shot
所以偶尔会看到一些射手摆弓姿势会变
For that reason, you may see some archers deviate from their normal follow-through
一些顶级射手，可能平常习惯向内摆
For someone who is a top-level shooter who might be always swinging inwards and twirling around
而某次射击却突然向外摆了
some shots might involve them actually popping out this way suddenly
这可能是因为他们后背肌肉张力发生了改变
and it may be because of a different level of tension in their back
他们当时可能是在瞄准
They might be forcing a shot through a certain way
可能在抵抗赛场上的风，但他们的目标仍然是靶心
They might be counteracting wind, but their shot is still on target
箭射出去之后怎样不重要，射手可能发现这局某些因素不太一样
The follow-through doesn't matter for the archer. They may have recognize that they have
而他们会相应的作出射箭动作上的改变
done something different and they will internally reflect on that shot process
但无论怎样，箭都是瞄着靶心射出去的，之后怎样做无所谓
but the shot already happened. What they do here doesn't matter
对于复合弓射手来说，摆弓动作就更少了
The lack of follow-through is more evident with compound shooters
你可能会注意到许多俱乐部级别的复合弓射手会用腕部弓绳
You will find that many club level compound shooters will make use of a wrist sling
一些标靶复合弓射手会用手指弓绳，但其实更多的是压根不摆弓的
Some target compound shooters will use a finger sling but many compound shooters don't bother with sling at all
当你能对弓做出操作之前，箭早就射出去了
The arrow will leave the bow far before you actually do something with the bow itself
所以你很少看到复合弓射手摆弓
You won't see many compound shooters with that swing
这也是为什么很多人认为摆弓是竞赛级反曲弓的独有技术
That's why many people recognize it as more of an Olympic recurve technique
虽然这根本不是啥技术
even though it technically isn't a technique
只是射箭之后的自然动作罢了。如果你用的不是竞赛级反曲弓
It's just a consequence of the shot process. If you're not shooting Olympic recurve
你也不用去摆弓，因为摆弓对你射箭成绩没有任何buff，就那么回事
there's no need to replicate the twirl. It doesn't add anything. It's really just superficial
甭管你怎样射，你需要记住的就是
For those shooting other styles, what you should keep in mind is
持弓手尽量放松就行了
to make sure your grip is as relaxed as possible
对于初学者，想练习正确持弓姿势的
For those who are starting out shooting and wanting to learn good form and good grip
只要记住用两只手指虎口夹住就行了
often they just use two fingers around the grip
这样不需要弓绳就能让弓稳稳搭在虎口上
so that way they don't grip the entire bow but they still retain it without using a finger sling
当然啦，许多射手练习的时候要求使用弓绳来矫正握姿
Many archers will be told to use the sling to get them used to the correct grip
如果你射的是裸弓，不用参加比赛，你也应该试试弓绳
If you're shooting barebow and you're not competing you still might want to give a finger sling a try
很多人持弓姿势错误自己却浑然不知
Many of your form faults may be caused by the bow grip and you might not realize it
总之，希望视频解答了大家的疑问，感谢观看
Anyway, I hope that answers your question. Thank you for watching
我是牛老师，字幕翻译给虫，记得投币点赞收藏分享关注哦
This is NUSensei. I'll see you next time.